I've decided that biohybrid robotics are
the brain rot of the engineering world.
There's simply no other explanation.
Some researchers made this little
bipeedal robot. It can walk underwater
and it's made of human muscle tissue. It
can walk, I guess, and turn around and
that's something that they've had
difficulty designing. As far as robotics
go, bipeds are just not the greatest
design. They fall over really easily.
So, they assembled this little balloon
on top so it stays upright, but it's
weighted just right. I'm not entirely
sure what the use of it is, but it can
be stimulated and the muscles work just
like ours. Theoretically, they could
live, grow, and heal. Now, if you do
want an underwater robot, I guess that's
fine. I don't know why it needs to walk
because there are biohybrid robots that
can function underwater. I mean, you can
turn a whole jellyfish into a robot. All
you have to do is just slip some
electrodes underneath its skin and
control it with a Raspberry Pi. You can
even use the jellyfish's body itself as
a processor. It's called physical
reservoir computing and essentially uses
the jellyfish's nonlinear movements
itself as a form of artificial
intelligence. Is that artificial
intelligence at that point or is it just
intelligence? Now, we do know that
jellyfish have memory. Some jellyfish
can even look at trees above the water
and use that to navigate. So, chances
are they probably traumatized it in some
way, shape, or form by turning it into a
computer. But yeah, from the absolutely
unhinged bio-hybrid robot dog that I've
covered, something that does not need to
exist in any way, shape, or form, but
somebody still imagined up and made a
paper about it. How to make a robot as
biological as possible. and the flesh
thing that I will never stop showing you
guys until it stops haunting my dreams.
This entire field is just the brain rot
of engineering and somehow I can't look
away. Probably for the same reasons we
all do. And because this stuff is always
on my mind, yes, you could control a
robot like this with a brain organoid
pretty easily because you can connect a
brain organoid to muscle tissue. If
you're not familiar with the brain
organoids, they are the tiny human
brains that we can grow from stem cells
and they can run a computer. They can
act as a processor. They're largely
valuable for medical research because
you can model human brains on the micro
scale. You can even have upwards of a
million neurons in one. No, they are not
conscious. They are technically
considered sentient because they are
capable of having an experience. And
when you use them for computation, they
are trained on dopamine. They enjoy
order. If you send disordered electrical
signals to them, they will try to
correct it because they don't enjoy
that. If you were to assign the word
enjoy to a disembodied clump of neurons
that yes can run a robot. This research
group attached them to some muscles and
they can learn to use the muscles. One
of the most unhinged papers that I've
covered involved taking brain organoids
and growing them near the decapitated
body of a mouse. And yes, they grew
projections directly into its spinal
cord and could even use the muscles.
They're intelligent in a way, but
they're still, you know, a clump of
brain tissue just doing brain tissue
things. I do find it really interesting
that they can learn to say navigate
through a maze. This is the best picture
I could find of this little robot that
was being trained on brain organoids. It
didn't technically have visual
information, but every time it was
starting to go in the wrong direction
away from its target, they sent
disordered signals. And the brain
organoids would try to fix that because
they just don't like disorder. And
honestly, I can't relate. I love chaos.
Oh, and if you're not familiar with the
flesh thing, it's living, breathing skin
tissue made from human cells that you
can coat a robot in. If you really want
to have to give your robot penicellin
when it nicks itself on the corner of
the table, that that's the use of it. By
the way, if you want access to any of
this stuff, I always link them directly
in the YouTube descriptions. I have
people perpetually asking me for
sources. It's right there. I usually
have the titles in the background of my
videos. Those those titles. If you do
not have direct access through a
university or a school, there are other
channels and I'll help you find those.
Knowledge should be for everyone. I do
have very strong feelings that if
research is going to be performed by
public funding, it should be available
to the public. Science is hard enough to
read. And adding additional barriers is
not good for literacy. I also wasn't
kidding about this haunting my dreams.